<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="nwod_category_statistics">
        <item name="Workforce_New_West_Resident_Commuting_Patterns_NHS_2011">Workforce_New_West_Resident_Commuting_Patterns_NHS_2011|This file contains information on the commuting patterns of workers who live in New Westminster (regardless of which municipality their place of work is located in). The information is from the 2011 National Household Survey and contains mode of transportation, time leaving for work, commute duration and commuting destinations. Also contains descriptive information about the data source files and notes about the use of the data.</item>
        <item name="Workforce_New_West_Worker_Commuting_Patterns_NHS_2011">Workforce_New_West_Worker_Commuting_Patterns_NHS_2011|Contains information on workers who work within the boundaries of the City of New Westminster (regardless of their municipality of residence).</item>
        <item name="Workforce_Profile_NHS_2011">Workforce_Profile_NHS_2011|2011 National Household Survey information on workers who work in New Westminster (regardless of municipality of residence). Information includes occupation, industry, employment income (before-tax), work activity, age and sex and education. Also contains descriptive information about the data source files and notes about the use of the data. </item>
        <item name="Oil_Tanks_Removed_Decommissioned">Oil_Tanks_Removed_Decommissioned|The number of underground storage tanks that are active, removed, or outstanding in the removal process, by year.</item>
        <item name="Number_of_City_Employees">Number_of_City_Employees|Financial Disclosure form completed annual by all elected officials. Number of city employees by year.</item>
        <item name="ICBC_Crash_Data">ICBC_Crash_Data|Lower mainland crashes</item>
        <item name="Historical_Development_Statistics">Historical_Development_Statistics|Statistics per Hectare show a sample of four types of uses or content in a particular block/area; the number of residences, the number of buildings, the floor space ratio which is the ratio of a buildings total floor area to the size of the land upon which it is built, and the number of parking spaces on property in the area. </item>
        <item name="Grants_Awarded_for_2016">Grants_Awarded_for_2016|A spreadsheet and accompanying documents listing grants awarded for year 2016.</item>
        <item name="Fire_Incidents_by_Year">Fire_Incidents_by_Year|Fire incidents by year.  The total number of incidents is broken down into reportable to the Office of the Fire Commissioner and non reportable.</item>
        <item name="Election_Results_1990_Present">Election_Results_1990_Present|The spreadsheet provides the candidates, voting locations and the results for the candidate both total and by location for each election from 1990 forward.</item>
        <item name="Emergency_Incidents_By_Fire_Hall">Emergency_Incidents_By_Fire_Hall|Emergency incident types by year by hall.  The total of yearly calls is also represented.</item>
        <item name="Emergency_Incidents_By_Fire_Hall_Summary">Emergency_Incidents_By_Fire_Hall_Summary|Emergency incident summary counts for past five years by hall. The total monthly and yearly calls are represented.</item>
        <item name="Emergency_Incidents_by_Type_Fire_and_Rescue_Services">Emergency_Incidents_by_Type_Fire_and_Rescue_Services|Incident types by month/year.  The total and percentage of incidents of total calls is also represented.  Only the current year is available in .csv.</item>
        <item name="Demographic_Detailed_Age_Profile_Census_2011">Demographic_Detailed_Age_Profile_Census_2011|Census 2011 information summarized by ages (by individual years of age and age groupings) and gender,  neighborhoods, census tracts and dissemination areas. Also contains descriptive information about the data source files and notes about the use of the data.</item>
        <item name="Demographic_Profiles_Census_1986_1991_1996_2001_2006">Demographic_Profiles_Census_1986_1991_1996_2001_2006|Information for the City of New Westminster from the 1986, 1991, 1996, 2001 and 2006 Censuses.</item>
        <item name="Demographic_Profiles_Census_2011">Demographic_Profiles_Census_2011|2011 census information summarized by </item>
        <item name="Demographic_Profiles_National_Household_Survey_2011">Demographic_Profiles_National_Household_Survey_2011|Contains tabs with 2011 National Household Survey information for the City of New Westminster, New Westminster neighbourhoods and New Westminster census tracts. National Household Survey includes information on income, housing characteristics, ethnicity, immigration, education, labour force etc. Also contains descriptive information about the data source files and notes about the use of the data.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="nwod_category_infrastructure">
        <item name="Drinking_Fountains">Drinking_Fountains|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Street_Features">Street_Features|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Street_Names">Street_Names|List of all current in-use street names used within the City. </item>
        <item name="Street_Network">Street_Network|Street centerlines and road classification</item>
        <item name="Traffic_Controllers_Signals">Traffic_Controllers_Signals|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Traffic_Volumes">Traffic_Volumes|Traffic volume counts at midblock points between the years 2006 and 2016 inclusive. </item>
        <item name="Tree_Inventory_East">Tree_Inventory_East|Street trees do more than beautify our City and create community pride. Street trees have been scientifically proven to: save energy by reduce heating or cooling costs for buildings they cover calm traffic clean air filter dust absorb sound cool area under tree and absorb humidity provide habitats for birds, mammals and insects</item>
        <item name="Tree_Inventory_West">Tree_Inventory_West|Street trees do more than beautify our City and create community pride. Street trees have been scientifically proven to: save energy by reduce heating or cooling costs for buildings they cover calm traffic clean air filter dust absorb sound cool area under tree and absorb humidity provide habitats for birds, mammals and insects</item>
        <item name="Truck_Routes">Truck_Routes|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Zoning">Zoning|The City of New Westminster Zoning Bylaw No. 6680 was adopted by Council September 17, 2001. Subsequent amendments to the Zoning Bylaw are consolidated for convenience only. For accurate interpretation, the public is encouraged to consult the Official Zoning Bylaw (including maps and amendments) available for viewing at City Hall in the Planning Division or Legislative Services Department.</item>
        <item name="Schedule_of_Goods_and_Services_2015">Schedule_of_Goods_and_Services_2015|Excel listing of all suppliers and service provides in the report period, plus the amount paid</item>
        <item name="School_Buildings">School_Buildings|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="School_Catchment_Boundaries">School_Catchment_Boundaries|Primary, Middle and Secondary School Boundaries.</item>
        <item name="School_Sites">School_Sites|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="School_Walking_Routes">School_Walking_Routes|Walking to school promotes healthy and safe communities benefiting children, families, and the earth.</item>
        <item name="Sewer_Catchbasins">Sewer_Catchbasins|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Sewer_Culverts">Sewer_Culverts|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Sewer_Ditches">Sewer_Ditches|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Sewer_Mains">Sewer_Mains|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Sewer_Maintenance_Holes">Sewer_Maintenance_Holes|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Sidewalk_Café_Location_Sidewalk_Encroachment_Agreements">Sidewalk_Café_Location_Sidewalk_Encroachment_Agreements|List of the locations of all Sidewalk Encroachment Agreements</item>
        <item name="SkyTrain_Centreline">SkyTrain_Centreline|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="SkyTrain_Stations">SkyTrain_Stations|SkyTrain Stations within New Westminster shown as footprints of the structure shapes. </item>
        <item name="SkyTrain_Stations_Points">SkyTrain_Stations_Points|SkyTrain Stations within New Westminster shown as point locations. </item>
        <item name="Off_Leash_Dog_Areas">Off_Leash_Dog_Areas|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Park_Benches_and_Dedications">Park_Benches_and_Dedications|Park benches locations throughout the city.</item>
        <item name="Park_Greenspaces">Park_Greenspaces|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Park_Structures">Park_Structures|Park Structure data will include the structure name, structure type, quantity, monument dedication inscription, furnishing photo graph (as available) park name and/or location.  The types of park structures included in the collection are •   Bleachers •   drinking fountains •   Park Lighting •   Monuments •   Basketball hoops •   Horticultural Planting Areas •   Picnic Tables</item>
        <item name="Park_Trails">Park_Trails|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Parking_Pay_Stations">Parking_Pay_Stations|Identifies the locations of all multi-space digital pay stations for parking in the City. </item>
        <item name="Parks">Parks|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Neighbourhoods_Boundaries">Neighbourhoods_Boundaries|These new boundaries are used for contemporary planning functions and are the basis for most of the statistics used in recent Census data published by the City of New Westminster. The boundaries for all neighbourhoods except for Downtown, North Arm North and Queens Park are the same for the redefined neighbourhood boundaries as in the original neighbourhood boundaries. </item>
        <item name="Landuse_Percentages_by_block">Landuse_Percentages_by_block|he Landuse Percentages show what proportion of a block/area has a particular use (e.g., being used for Commercial purposes or Single Family Residences). </item>
        <item name="Land_Use">Land_Use|Land use represents what a parcel of land is currently being used for (i.e., the land parcel’s primary use). The land use shown in this layer does not necessarily reflect the zoning or the OCP designation of the land.</item>
        <item name="Land_Use_Industrial">Land_Use_Industrial|Land use represents what a parcel of land is currently being used for (i.e., the land parcel’s primary use). The land use shown in this layer does not necessarily reflect the zoning or the OCP designation of the land.</item>
        <item name="Intersections">Intersections|The junctions at-grade of two or more roads either meeting or crossing. </item>
        <item name="Greenways">Greenways|Greenways provide important cycling routes across the City connecting from one community to another and between major parks.</item>
        <item name="Accessible_Public_Washrooms">Accessible_Public_Washrooms|Listing of all the accessible washrooms that are available within the City.</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="nwod_category_facilities_and_services">
        <item name="Public_Art">Public_Art|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Railways">Railways|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Riparian">Riparian|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Police_Buildings">Police_Buildings|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Hospital_Buildings">Hospital_Buildings|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Heritage_Register">Heritage_Register|Official listing of properties deemed to have heritage value. </item>
        <item name="Heritage_Resource_Inventory">Heritage_Resource_Inventory|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Fire_and_Rescue_Services_Buildings">Fire_and_Rescue_Services_Buildings|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="City_Facility_Buildings">City_Facility_Buildings|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="City_Facility_Sites">City_Facility_Sites|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Alternative_Fuels_and_Electric_Charging_Stations">Alternative_Fuels_and_Electric_Charging_Stations|Electric vehicles are an environmentally friendly mode of transportation. As cleaner emission vehicles gain momentum across the lower mainland, the City of New Westminster is putting itself on the map alongside leading municipalities by incorporating electric vehicles into the City\'s automotive fleet and installing electric vehicle charging stations in the community.</item>
        <item name="Cemeteries">Cemeteries|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Community_Conversation_on_Housing_Comments_Our_City_2014">Community_Conversation_on_Housing_Comments_Our_City_2014|Got to </item>
        <item name="Community_Service_Assets">Community_Service_Assets|A listing of community services and supports. More specifically, it includes information on emergency, transitional and supportive housing; transition and second stage housing for women; addiction and mental health services; drop-in and meal programs; education and job training opportunities; and government services.</item>
        <item name="Contours">Contours|1 meter intervals</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="nwod_category_economy_and_living">
        <item name="Financial_Disclosure_Statements">Financial_Disclosure_Statements|This form is a mandated requirement of the Provincial government and is completed annually.</item>
        <item name="Statement_of_Financial_Information_2015">Statement_of_Financial_Information_2015|Remuneration of City Employees and Council Members</item>
        <item name="Webcam_Links">Webcam_Links|Active webcam locations in New Westminster. </item>
        <item name="Wheelchair_Ramps">Wheelchair_Ramps|No Description Available</item>
        <item name="Water_Hydrants">Water_Hydrants|A hydrant is an outlet from a fluid main often consisting of an upright pipe with a valve attached from which fluid (e.g. water or fuel) can be tapped.</item>
        <item name="Water_Pressure_Zones">Water_Pressure_Zones|This polygon feature class represents each water pressure zone in the City of New Westminster water distribution system. The data was developed to represent the location of water pressure zones for the purpose of mapping, analysis, planning and maintenance of utilities. The accuracy of this data varies and should not be used for precise measurements or calculations.</item>
        <item name="Water_Quality_Data">Water_Quality_Data|A hydrant is an outlet from a fluid main often consisting of an upright pipe with a valve attached from which fluid (e.g. water or fuel) can be tapped. This data set presents the raw data from which our Annual Water Quality report is generated.  For full context for the data please refer to the report.</item>
        <item name="Water_Valves">Water_Valves|A device that regulates the flow of water.</item>
        <item name="Watermains">Watermains|A principal pipe in a system of pipes for conveying water, especially one installed underground.</item>
        <item name="Business_Licenses_Active_Resident">Business_Licenses_Active_Resident|New Westminster has an annual renewal of approximately 4,000 business licenses each year. Business Licensing also issues licenses for liquor establishments and municipal decals.</item>
        <item name="Business_Licenses_Inter_Municipal">Business_Licenses_Inter_Municipal|As of October 1, 2013, an Inter-municipal Business License will be available in the Metro West region. For $250, eligible businesses may be licensed to work in all of the following municipalities: </item>
        <item name="Business_Licenses_New_for_2016">Business_Licenses_New_for_2016|Every business in the City of New Westminster is required to have a valid business license before beginning operation. This includes home-based businesses, commercial and industrial operations and owners of apartment rental properties.</item>
        <item name="Business_Licenses_Non_Residents">Business_Licenses_Non_Residents|Contractors from different municipalities doing business within New Westminster</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="nwod_category_other">
        <item name="Orthophotography">Orthophotography|Aerial photography over the City of New Westminster</item>
        <item name="Addresses">Addresses|A list of addresses for the City of New Westminster.</item>
        <item name="Block_Reference_File">Block_Reference_File|The blocks correspond to a division of the City into about 400 blocks, set up by the City Planner in about 1970. The purpose of these geographic descriptions was to enable more rapid tallying of information by subareas of the City. The geographic subdivision keys would provide easier selection of which properties to include in a run for a report without having to rely on property folio designations which are subject to change, consolidation and subdivision.</item>
        <item name="Building_Age">Building_Age|The age of most buildings in the City (year it was built) as well as some historical data such as the Building Name, Developer/Builder, Architect/Designer and year the building has been moved if relevant and available. </item>
        <item name="Building_Attributes">Building_Attributes|Building development specifics including the number of floors above and below ground, the number of residential units, square footage, size of the footprint and site coverage, and address. </item>
        <item name="Building_Footprints">Building_Footprints|Outlines of buildings.  All primary buildings such as residential and commerical are included.</item>
        <item name="Bike_Routes">Bike_Routes|This dataset contains bike routes including planned and current bikeways, on-street and off-street, as well as dedicated lanes. </item>
        <item name="City_Boundaries">City_Boundaries|City of New Westminster Boundaries. </item>
        <item name="City_Energy_Use_Through_Time">City_Energy_Use_Through_Time|Financial disclosure form completed annually by all elected officials. Shows the amount of energy consumed and greenhouse gases created through time.</item>
        <item name="City_Owned_Property">City_Owned_Property|Parcels of property currently owned by the Corporation of the City of New Westminster. </item>
        <item name="Councillor_Contact_Information">Councillor_Contact_Information|The City of New Westminster wants to facilitate residents and the general public access to the elected officials of the City.  </item>
        <item name="Parcel_Blocks">Parcel_Blocks|Block outlines of contiguous aggregated parcels. </item>
        <item name="Parcels">Parcels|When you download datasets, you are agreeing to </item>
        <item name="Projects_on_the_Go">Projects_on_the_Go|Current applications for rezoning, development permit and heritage revitalization agreement projects currently being processed by the City, including application status, architect/ developer information, and staff contact.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>
